Md Mehedi Hasan

📞 +880 1913 642412 | 🗣 Dhaka, Bangladesh 🗷 md.mehedi.info@gmail.com 🜎 github.com/gitmehedi | 🥠 leetcode.com/gitmehedi | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/gitmehedi

PROFILE

I am an experienced tech lead with over 10 years of experience in full-stack software development. I have developed a strong understanding of software and ERP implementation, and Im passionate about delivering highquality, highimpact technology solutions. I excel at collaborating with stakeholders to identify user needs, design roadmaps, and manage projects.

EXPERIENCE

Solutions Engineer

March. 2023 - Present

Notun Kichu

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Gathering early non-functional requirements and evaluating functional requirements captured by a business analyst
- Evaluating functional requirements captured by a business analyst
- · Designing a high-level architect and choosing the right technology stack and deployment methods with estimating development time
- Skills: Python, PostgreSQL, Odoo, Django, Docker, Ubuntu, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Project Management, Project Esmitation, Client Management, BRS, SRS, Time Management, Strategic Planning

Principal Software Engineer

April. 2021 - Feb. 2023

Genweb2 Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Design application architecture for software and deployment
- Manage team for proper project delivery
- Skills: Python, Odoo, PostgreSQL, Redhat, DB Clustering, Docker, High Available, Project Management, Client Management, BRS, Team Management, Strategic Planning

Senior Software Engineer

March 2019 - March 2021

Genweb2 Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Design highly available architecture and deploy ERP application on that architecture.
- Design, develop, and implement a financial application for a local banking system with TCS core banking integration.
- Skills: Python, Odoo, PostgreSQL, Ubuntu, Docker, Git, Jenkins, BRS, Team Management, Time Management, Scrum

Software Engineer

July 2016 - Feb. 2019

Genweb2 Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- · Implement ERP application for the garments industry with procurement, sales, and purchase modules.
- Design, develop, and deploy applications for several business domains.
- Skills: Python, Odoo, PostgreSQL, Ubuntu, Nginx

Junior Software Engineer

July 2012 - June 2016

Genweb2 Limited

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- · Implement online music listening application using PHP, MySQL, JQuery, Cache for international client
- Prepare SRS documentation for defense organization
- Skills: PHP, MySQL, Symphony, ZF1, ZF2, Caching, JQuery, Ubuntu

PROJECTS

Hospital Management System

- · Design scalable hospital management system with microservice
- · Serve service to a large user group based on service demand
- Stack: Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, REST, React, PostgreSQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Documentation

General Ledger For Core Banking

- Developed Accounting, Purchase, TPM, Rental Agreement, Fixed Asset Management for banking user
- Design and develop high available backend server architecture in on-premise
- · Ensure support to application user with ensuring future development

Edward M. Kennedy Center ERP Management

- Developed Sales, Purchase, Event Management, Appointment Booking, Accounting, and HR Management modules for ERP application
- Skills: Python, Odoo, Nginx, PostgreSQL, Linux

Samuda Chemical Limited ERP Management

- Developed Sales, Purchase, HR Management, Procurement, Salary Generation, Attendance Management, and Accounting modules for ERP application
- · Skills: Python, Odoo, Nginx, PostgreSQL, Linux, AWS

Pebbles ERP Management and Lakhsma ERP Management

- · Built an ERP application for manufacturing units
- Built an Odoo application with Sales, Purchase, and Point of Sales business functionality which covers online and offline sales features
- · Skills: Python, Odoo, Nginx, PostgreSQL, Ubuntu

Ration, POL Management for Bangladesh Army

 Automate functional features for Ration distribution, Petrol, oil, and lubricants departments using PHP, MySQL, Ubuntu, and JQuery

Indishuffle Online Music

Online Music Listening application for large-scale user group using PHP, MySQL, Linux, Cache, JavaScript, JQuery

EDUCATION

M.Sc in Information and Communication Engineering

Islamic University, Bangladesh

2010 - 2011

Dhaka, Bangladesh

B.Sc in Information and Communication Engineering

Islamic University, Bangladesh

2006 - 2010

Dhaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS

Language: Python, Odoo, Flask, Django, Django (DRF), JavaScript, React, Backbone, PHP, Kafka, RabbitMQ, RestAPI, Shell

Server: Docker, Docker Composer, Kubernetes, Ubuntu, Redhat, AWS, High-Availability, Nginx, Load Balancer

Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, PostgreSQL Clustering

Tools: Scrum, Git, Github, Gitlab, Jira, PyCharm, Jenkins, ElasticSearch, Kibana, LogStash

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

By Cloud Native Computing Foundation

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)

By Cloud Native Computing Foundation

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM)

By Scrum Alliance

August, 2020

Certificate ID: LF-n525ephyjj

February, 2021

Certificate ID: LF-kaleuahyc3

December, 2022

Certificate ID: 001454993